Let us deviate the discussion a bit from here.  Let's go
today to talk to ICC member Lomborg.
CFO
Mr. Gopal Balchandan is present with us.
Hello Sir, welcome to the program.  First of all,
Sir, I would like to focus a little with you on the highlights of this quarter.  According to you,
what was important in this quarter, which
for you means a little bit that had an
impact, especially on the profit figures,
some important aspects, the
industry growth this quarter was almost single
digit number, around 6%, in that
context, if you would have
seen the growth of ICMBARD, we have been at about 8.2%,
so this is what we had said that relative to the
industry, the growth of ICMBARD will be, we will have an
out performance and at the end
of the year, I think we have been able to kind of
sustain that, in so far as the outcome
is concern, so far as premiums are concern
and revenues are concern and same thing, if
you would have seen in so far as the combined
ratio, when it comes to our combined ratio, every year we have been
showing sign of declines year on
year, in the treasury,
it has been seeing a
decline, two years ago our combined
ratio was around 13, around 105, then  104
last year's combined that was about
103 so 3.3 if you have
seen the combined ratio of FI 25 ICC low that is
102.8%.  So clearly our thought
process which I said is to drive
profitable businesses, we kept focusing largely on that
and hence the outcome in so far as
combined is concern again that has been very very
positive.  Ah and the
third thing that we have always been telling the market is
that our return on
expectations
for equity shareholders, broadly the range that we had
talked about was between 16% to 18%,
if you have seen our return on
equity for a full year basis that has been
roughly at about 19%,
well but I had seen sir that if I
compare it with the last quarter, there is
an improvement in your combined ratio but
still profitably this counter is down.
Sir, was there any one-off item among your members this time
?   The
outcome of our capital gas will be
significantly cyclical.  One quarter may
not be necessarily
comparable to another.  And that's because we always say
that the way we look at our numbers
is you have to always look at it more on an
annualized basis as compared to quarter
on quarter.  So that's the reason why the
profit number you see is
relatively lower in Q4 compared to on a full
year basis.  But your point on
combined ratio again to address that the
combined ratio for quarter four of this year
on a reported basis is
102.5, the same number in quarter four of
last year was 102.3, but if you remember
what I had said in the last quarter also that the
regulator had brought a change effective October one this year, particularly
for long term policies,
where it had
said that the revenue recognition philosophy of the insurance company selling long term
policies will be only allowed to be
recognized only on a yearly basis
on a year on year basis.  So during that change,
if you would have seen that our
combined 102.5, if we have to compare it on a same to same
basis, then that
number will actually be at 102.1, so
actually there is an improvement even if you
look at it from quarter four to quarter 4
and again whether you look at Q4 or whether
you look at on a full year basis, as I
said, our trajectory in terms of
improvement in combined that is something that we are very very
confident of.
Well Sir, as you
said in the introduction itself that now you are using AI and
technology for I think product
distribution, what impact has it had, will
you share that with us a little bit
and has it become better than the traditional distribution method,
I
mean, is the digital distribution that you are doing
now gaining a little bit of an edge
due to this,
so if you see, it is very useful in different segments.
So let's take health
insurance.  If you talk about health,
when a claim comes, the first point that the
customer keeps in mind is to get the authorization
approval from the hospital quickly.  When we
go for treatment, we
obviously expect that our approval
process from an insurance
company has to be very very fast.
And there if you look again from an
ICOM stand point for a very large number
of procedures that we approve.
In fact, the time it takes to process an
authorization request is less than 90
seconds.
So Hans, we use a lot of technology there too.  A
lot of AIML is what we kind
of apply and so again if we
talk about customer experience, that is what we want to kind
of create and the
feedback is again
reflective in the net promoter scores that
customers give in terms of their
experience of our service.  If you have noticed, whether
in health or motor, our
NPS scores have been very very high.
We are ok thank you very much sir
for this entire conversation, I was having a
special conversation with Mr. Gopal Balachandan regarding the members,
thank you very much sir
for joining this program and best of luck for the
next
quarter Nifty is moving a little bit from the higher level
and that